翻译校对       Mam
日  听      大海
日听校对       Syura
翻译        墨墨
时间轴       黑猫与牛奶
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Okay then,
じゃさあ
which one of us is Hikaru,
and which one is Kaoru? Can you tell?
どっちが光で　どっちが馨か分かる？
You're Hikaru- kun.
こっちが光君
We were always two, yet one.
僕らはずっとふたりでひとつ
The two of us were a single, unique being.
僕らはふたりで唯一の存在
This was very important.
これは
"Eight years later..."
とっても大切なこと
"Hikaru and Kaoru's
2nd year of middle school"
But we were separate beings.
The one that wasn't me
だけど僕らは別々の存在
僕じゃないほうが光で
was Hikaru, and the one
that wasn't Hikaru was me.
光じゃないほうが僕
For us, this was something that was...
そのことは僕らにとって…
She's here.
来たよ
Yeah, you're right.
ああ　本当だ
Sorry, I must have kept you waiting.
ごめんね　待ったでしょう
I read your letter.
手紙読んだよ
Hikaru- kun...
光君
No, I'm sorry, but I
いや　悪いけど　僕  馨のほう
am Kaoru.
君　僕と光の机間違えて手紙入れたでしょう
You must have mistaken
my desk for Hikaru's
when you put the letter in it.
Even so, would you mind if it was me?
でもさ　僕じゃダメかな
The truth is, I've always
thought that you were cute.
実は僕　君のことずっと可愛いって思ってたんだ
And Hikaru seems to have
another girl that he likes.
光は他に好きな子がいるみたいだし
Well, would you mind?
Um, I...
あの　わたし　わたしも馨君さえよければ…
if I'm okay for you, Kaoru- kun...
Hey, Kaoru!
おい　馨　この子お前でもいいってさ
She says that she'd be fine with you.
You're really Hikaru- kun?
あなた　本物の光君？
That was no fun. I'm getting
tired of this same old pattern.
つまんないの　このパターンももう飽きたなあ
How mean of you! How mean of you!
ひどい　ひどいわ
You're the one who's mean, aren't you?
ひどいのはそっちでしょう
You're okay with either one of us?
Who do you think you are?
どっちでもいいなんて
君何様なわけ
Another thing, that hairstyle
doesn't look good on you.
それと君　その髪型似合ってないよ
If you want us to go out with you,
brush up on your fashion sense.
僕らとお付き合いしたけりゃ　センス磨いて
次はもっと面白い告白してね
Next time, make your love
confession more interesting.
That was a mean thing to do, huh?
ひどいことするね
Are you all right, my cute young lady?
大丈夫　可愛いお嬢さん
Kaoru, want to play a game?
馨　ゲームする？
"5th period, study hall"
I found an interesting site.
面白いサイト見つけたんだ
What about that net game from before?
この間のネットゲームは？
I'm tired of it already.
They're all a bunch of weaklings.
もう飽きたよ　弱い奴らばっかでさ
It's no fun, is it?
つまんねぇじゃん
Yeah, you're right. Never mind.
そうだね　もういいか
Whenever anything was no fun,
we'd get rid of it immediately.
つまらないものはさっさと消去
That was our motto.
それが僕らのモットー
Those Hitachiin twins are horrible, huh?
常陸院の双子っておっかないよな
They're always looking down on everyone.
いつも人を見下してるしさあ
But my dad told me to get along with them.
でも　父が仲良くしておけって
Yeah, mine too.
うちもさ
Mine, too.
うちも
I'm sure they've never liked
anyone besides themselves.
きっと自分たち以外は誰も好きになったことないんだろうな
That wasn't true. Up until then,
there was just one person,
それは違う
僕らには　これまでたったひとりだけ
a lady maid, who we were very fond of.
僕らがとても気に入った世話係のお姉さんがいた
"10 years earlier"
That was quite a while ago, though.
もうずいぶん前のことだけど
"Hitachiin Manor, courtyard"
Oh, my, how cute you look today!
まあまあ　今日もなんて可愛らしいんでしょう
Just like little dolls.
まるでお人形さんみたい
The one with blue hair is Hikaru- kun,
and pink, Kaoru- kun, right?
蒼い髪が光君で　ピンクが馨君だったかしら？
Wrong, auntie. The blue one is Kaoru,
and the pink one is Hikaru.
違うよ　おばさん
蒼が馨でピンクが光
You always get it wrong.
You must be dumb.
いつも間違えてバッカみたい
I'm sorry. You two really
do look exactly alike.
ごめんなさいね　ふたりとも本当にそっくりだから
Auntie, you look exactly
like a frog. See?
おばさんは蛙にそっくりだけどね　ほら
Hey!
こらああ　お坊っちゃま方
Oh, you boys!
Madam, I'm sorry.
奥様　すみません
We liked that maid.
その世話係が好きだった
She was a little different
from the sycophants,
それまでのご機嫌取りや　愛想笑いの奴らとは少し違ったから
and the ingratiating types
that we'd had up until then.
What are you doing!?
何してるの？
Night exploring.
夜の探険
Since you've found me,
I've got no choice.
見つかったら仕方ない
You two are going to keep this quiet.
ふたりとも静かにしてもらうわよ
If we push this button,
このスイッチを押すと警備員が駆けつけるんだって
the security guards will
come running. Let's try it.
押してみよう
3... 2...
三　二…
ちょっ　やめて
Whoa, stop!
This is the combination to that safe.
その金庫の番号だよ
If you'll play with us...
僕らと遊んでくれたら
...we'd be willing
to give you this paper.
この紙あげてもいいんだけど
W-what do you want to play?
な　なにをして遊ぶのかな
The "which one is Hikaru- kun game"!
どっちが光君でしょうかゲーム
Hikaru, are you sure you have
the paper with the combination?
光　番号の紙ちゃんとある？
It's okay.
大丈夫　貯金箱に隠してあるから
I hid it in the coin bank. She can't
get it out without breaking it.
割らないと取り出せない
I'm sure that we wanted that lady
to be able to tell us apart.
僕たちはきっとそのお姉さんに見分けてほしかったんだと思う
We liked that lady, after all.
お姉さんが好きだったから
You broke your promise.
約束破ったなあ
I had no choice, did I?
I can't tell you two apart.
しょうがないでしょう
わたしにはあんたらを見分けることなんてできないよ
It's just possible that no one will
ever turn up in your whole life
もしかしたら
あんたらを本当に見分ける奴なんて一生現われないかもね
that can really tell you two apart.
The lady maid, the one
and only one we ever liked,
僕らが唯一気に入っていた世話係のお姉さんは
そう言い残して夜の闇に消えた
said that to us, and then disappeared
into the darkness of night.
We became progressively
more twisted as we grew up.
僕らは着実に捩じれて成長していった
And so, we kept putting
up a friendly barrier,
そして　気安く人を近付けさせないバリアーを張り続けた
to keep others from getting
too close. But even so,
それでも　そのバリアーに気付かないほど鈍い奴が
somebody too dense
to notice the barrier
would come along,
every once in a while.
極偶に近付いてきたりする
You two don't seem to be too occupied.
君たち暇そうだね
If you've got the time, what do you say?
Let's form a club together!
暇ならどうだ　俺と一緒に部を立ち上げよう
Who is this guy?
誰だこいつ
Ah, I know. All the girls in class
are clamoring about him.
僕知ってる　クラスの女の子が騒いでるだろう
You know, that guy Suou,
who was admitted last spring.
ほら　去年の春に編入してきた須王の…
Ah, so this is the guy, huh?
こいつがそうなのか
そうか　そうか　そんなにも俺は有名か
Really? Really? I'm that famous?
I feel so... guilty.
なんて罪深き俺
My brilliance, both within and without,
外見からも内面からも滲み出る輝きは
has reached all the way
to everyone's eyes, has it?
誰の目にも留まってしまうのか
"Tamaki Suou (middle school 3rd-year)"
Ah, i-is this what it is to have
the fortune of a man,
あ～こ　これが
神に魅入られてしまった男の宿命だと言うのか
possessed by God?
"Tamaki Suou, middle school 3rd-year
(mid-fantasy)"
Nobody ever said that.
そんなこと言ってないけど
Ah, but still, no need to worry.
Though perhaps not as great as mine,
いやしかし　安心したまえ
俺には及ばんかもしれんが
you two do show quite a bit of promise.
君たちもなかなか見所があるぞ
Look, what are you talking about?
あのね　なんの話？
I'm starting a new club in April,
two months from now.
部の始動は　二ヵ月後の四月からだ
I'm thinking, as soon as
I move up to the high school.
俺が高等部に上がったら　すぐにでもと考えている
We would have to have you come up
from the middle school for a year,
君たちは一年間　中等部から通ってもらうことになるが
but I'll put in a word for you
to take care of that.
その辺は俺が話を通しておくから
It will be so fun! I've also
got Otori Kyoya, from my class.
楽しいぞ
他には俺のクラスの鳳鏡夜だろう
"'The Setting Sun' by Dazai Osamu"
Additionally, high school
1st-Years Haninozuka- senpai
それから高等部一年の埴之塚先輩と銛之塚先輩を勧誘中だ
and Morinozuka- senpai
have been invited.
And that's where you two-
そこに君たちが…
You're bothering us. Go away.
うるさいな　どっか行ってよ
We don't hang out with anyone.
僕らは誰ともつるまないよ
We're not interested in you.
あんたなんかに興味ないの
If you absolutely must come near us...
どうしても僕らとお近付きになりたいんだったら
...will you play?
挑戦する
The "which one is Hikaru- kun game"!
どっちが光君でしょうかゲーム
You understand the meaning
of the game, right?
ゲームの意味は分かるよね
You just have to pick
which one of us is Hikaru.
僕らのどちらが光かを当てるだけ
期間は一ヵ月間
You have a one-month time limit.
In that time, you can try
as many times as you like,
その間は何度トライしてもいいけど
but we will ask you for your reasoning.
ちゃんと理由も聞くからね
No random guessing.
当てずっぽうはダメ
We should warn you,
言っとくけど　このゲームで正解出せた奴なんていないから
nobody has ever given the right
answer in this game before.
それでよけりゃ　せいぜい頑張って
If that's all right with you,
then try your best.
He's balking, he's balking.
怯んでる　怯んでる
Never mind him, did you
hear that lineup of his?
それより聞いたか　さっきのメンツ
I can see why he wants to add
the Hitachiin name to it.
あそこに常陸院の名を加えたいわけね
Is he just trying to create
a faction of highborns?
家柄重視の派閥でも作ろうってか
One month, right!?
一ヵ月だな
Very well. In return, if I win,
you have to join my club.
いいだろう　その代わり
俺が勝ったら　うちの部に入ってもらう
But I'm making a prediction.
だが俺は予言するぞ
楽室の扉を　きっと開く
Come April,
I'm sure that you two
will be opening the doors
to High School Music Room #3.
And so, our time-limit game had started.
こうして　僕らの期限付きゲームは
"Game start"
スタートした
Um, Hikaru- kun, Kaoru- kun,
あのう　光君　馨君
we're planning to have a class
event after closing ceremonies.
終業式の後にクラスイベントの企画があるんですけれど
Yeah, we'll pass.
ああ　僕らはパス
But, it's going to be the last
event of our second year.
でも　せっかく二年生最後のイベントだし
We're not all that pensive about it.
別に思い入れないし
The one who's reading
the book right now is Hikaru!
今本を読んでいるのが光
What is this, coming into
our classroom like this?
なんすか　人のクラスにまで来て
Am I right? Did I get it right?
当たりか　当たったのか
No, you didn't.
いや　当たってないし
俺は発見したぞ
I've discovered something!
Hikaru, you're right-handed!
光は右利きだ
Yeah, but both of us are right-handed.
いや　ふたりとも右利きだし
Also, Kaoru, you part
your hair on the right.
あと　馨は前髪が右わけだな
We're always switching hairstyles.
髪型しょっちゅう変えてるし
パートを担当しているのが
When you harmonize, the one
who takes the lower tone is-
What are we, a chorus!?
合唱かよ
Um... You're Suou- senpai, right?
あのう　須王先輩ですよね
Yes, I'm sorry. Did you need
something with these two?
ああ　ごめんね　ふたりに何か用だった
Yes, um, I was inviting them
to attend a class event.
え　あのう　クラスイベントの出欠を尋ねしていて
Hmm, a film festival?
That will be nice.
映画鑑賞会か　いいね
I'll just circle Hikaru
and Kaoru as attending.
光と馨も出席　丸と
勝手に決めんな
Don't you go deciding for us!
Hey, were are you going!?
おい　どこへ行くのだ
帰る　あんたうるさいし
We're leaving. You're annoying.
What about our game!?
ゲームはどうするのだ
I thought we told you.
だから言ってるじゃん
Try your best.
せいぜい頑張って
"'No Longer Human' by Dazai Osamu"
I thought you went to go see the twins.
双子に会いに行ったんじゃないのか
No, they ran away on me.
いや　逃げられた
Help me out, here.
This is for the club, right?
お前も協力しろよ　部のためだろう
No biggie. We can still form
the club without them, right?
別にあのふたりじゃなくても部は立ち上げられるだろう
No, I have an interest in those two.
ダメだ　俺はあのふたりに興味があるんだ
Are they some more of "our friends"
that you were talking about?
あいつらも　お前がいうところの「俺たちの仲間」なのか
Oh... mm-hmm.
Then again, what are they thinking?
If they wanted to be told apart,
しかしあいつら　なに考えてんだ
見分けてほしいなら
they could just change their
hairstyles, or something.
髪型変えるなりすればいいのに
Then they don't want to be told apart.
見分けてほしくないんだろう
But the game is to tell them apart.
でも　見分けろっていうゲームだぞ
Then they do want to be told apart.
じゃ見分けてほしいんだろう
お前ちゃんと話し聞いてる
Are you even listening
to what I'm saying?
About half of it.
半分ぐらいな
"The next morning,
Hitachiin Manor, front door"
This morning, the one parted
on the right is Kaoru,
今朝は右わけが馨で　左わけが光
and the one parted
on the left is Hikaru!
Hey, good morning!
やあ　おはよう
What is this, coming
to our house like this?
なんすか　人の家まで来て
Am I right? Did I get it right?
当たりか　当たったのか
No, you didn't.
いや　当たってないし
I've discovered something!
俺は発見したぞ　馨は少し内股じゃないか
Kaoru, you're a bit
pigeon-toed, aren't you?
You should have that fixed.
直したほうがいい
How rude! That's not true!
失礼な　違うよ
I thought of something last night.
ゆうべ思い付いたんだがなあ
What if we let your
brotherly love be your draw?
君たちは兄弟愛を売りにしたらどうだろう
Huh?
A somewhat risky,
symmetrical, brotherly love.
ちょっと危ないシンメトリー兄弟愛
The Hitachiin Brothers!
常陸院ブラザーズ
これでどうだ
How about that!?
We don't know what you mean.
意味分かんない
Hey! Don't run away! Hold it!
こら　逃げるなあ　待てぇ
なんなの　あの人
What's with that guy?
Starting in, first thing in the morning...
こんな朝っぱらからさあ
You know, that tone he takes...
っていうか　あの口調
Yeah, yeah, I thought so too.
そうそう　僕も思った
殿様喋りだよね
He talks just like some feudal lord, huh?
Why, when he has such a princely face,
does he take that tone!?
なんであんな王子顔なのに
あの口調なんだよ
"Hold it!" he said! "Hold it!"
待てぇって言ってた　待てぇって
gozaru: somewhat archaic
Japanese copula verb
He seems like, before long, he'll
start using "gozaru," doesn't he?
そのうち「ござる」とか言い出しそうじゃない
He's a fool. A foolish lord.
馬鹿だ　馬鹿殿だ
Then again...
でもさあ
...we're starting to get tired of him, huh?
そろそろ飽きたよね
Huh?
Like we said, we're done.
だからさ　終わり
Game over.
ゲームオーバー
What are you talking about?
How self-serving!
なに言ってんだ　そんな勝手な…
そうなの　僕ら勝手なの
That's right. We are self-serving.
Or, should we say...
っていうかさあ
We heard you're the illegitimate
son of the superintendent, huh?
あんたって　理事長の本妻の子じゃないんだってね
Forgive us, but we did
a little looking in to you.
ごめんね　ちょっと調べちゃってさ
My, you've got quite a sad
little life story, don't you?
いや　結構可哀相な生い立ちなんだね
You wouldn't want us to spread
this around the school, right?
このこと　学校の奴らに言い触らされたくないっしょ
What's more, your actual mother
is still missing, even now.
しかも　実の母親は今も行方不明
Ultimately, you're just lonesome,
being by yourself, aren't you?
あんたは結局一人で寂しいだけなんだろう
So could you not arbitrarily
try to make us your friends?
だからって　勝手に僕らを仲間にしないでくれる
The two of us are still better
off than the one of you.
ひとりのあんたより　ふたりの僕らのほうがまだ増しさ
Let's go, Hikaru.
行こう　光
O-okay.
He won't go sticking his nose
into our business anymore.
これでもう　ちょっかい出して来ないだろう
Still, it's sort of a shame.
でも　ちょっと惜しかったかな
Maybe we could have toyed with
him a bit longer. Then again,
もう少し遊べたかもね
でもさ　もうがっかりさせられんのはごめんだしね
I'm not up for being disappointed again.
We were always inconsistent.
僕らは常に矛盾している
We wanted to be told apart.
We didn't want to be told apart.
ふたりを見分けてほしい　見分けてほしくない
We wanted people to know us.
We didn't want to be known.
僕らのことを知ってほしい　知ってほしくない
We were always looking for
someone who would accept us...
僕らは常に受け入れてくれる誰かを求めて
But there's no way that anyone
would ever accept anyone
だけど　こんな捻くれた僕らを受け入れてくれる人なんて
as surly as we were.
いるはずないから
We kept a very, very secure lock,
to make sure that no one
ずっとふたりきりの世界の中で
傷付かないで済むように
could ever hurt us,
in our own, two-person world.
とてもとても頑丈な鍵をかけている
Kaoru...
馨
She's here.
来たよ
ああ　本当だ
Yeah, you're right.
へえ　おい　光
Hey, Hikaru!
She says that she'd be fine with you.
この子お前でもいいってさ
Huh?
Ah, not again.
ああ　またか
For as sweet a face as you have,
あんた　大人しそうな顔してすごい性格してんだね
you sure have an awful personality, huh?
Saying that either one
of us would be fine...
どっちでもいいっていうのはさ
...really means that you don't
want either one of us, doesn't it?
本当はどっちもいらないってことじゃん
How mean of you! How mean of you!
ひどい　ひどいよ
Which one of us is really meaner?
本当にひどいのはどっちだよ
The one about to rip up
the letter is Hikaru!
今手紙を破こうとしているのが　光
H-how did you...
な　なんで
Am I right? Did I get it right?
当たりか　当たったのか
What's your reasoning?
理由は
Intuition!
勘だ
You know... I thought we told
you at the beginning
あのう　最初に当てずっぽうはダメって言ったはずだけど
that you couldn't just randomly guess.
Yeah, I'm sorry.
I just can't tell yet.
いや　すまんな
今のとこ　俺には無理だ
だって　そっくりすぎるぞ　お前ら
I mean, you're just too alike.
けどまあ　ものは考えようだ
But then, it all depends
on how you look at it.
As identical as you two are,
it's like you have a talent.
そこまでそっくりなのは　もはや才能だ
So from now on, work to perfect
the two-in-one Hitachiin Brothers.
だからこれからも
ふたりでひとりの常陸院ブラザーズを極めていけ
But you mustn't forget that you are
also independent beings, of course.
けど　もちろんお前らが別個の存在であることを忘れちゃいかん
Which is why I'm going to keep working
at being able to tell you two apart.
だから俺も頑張って　ふたりを見分けられるように努力するから
That's crazy.
そんなの変だよ
It's inconsistent.
矛盾してるよ
What are you talking about?
なに言ってんだよ
It may be inconsistent,
but it's who you are.
矛盾しててもそれがお前らだろうが
It's what we call individuality.
個性っていうんだよ　そういうのは
What are you talking about?
なに言ってんだ
If we start going with this " Hitachiin
Brothers" style, like you say,
あんたの言うとおりに常陸院ブラザーズなんてスタイル始めたら
then we'll be a set piece forever!
それこそ僕ら　永遠にセット売りだ
No matter how hard you try,
you'll never be able to tell us apart!
いくらあんたが頑張っても
絶対に僕らを見分けることなんてできない
We're the only people who are
able to tell ourselves apart.
僕らを見分けられる人間は
僕らしかいない
There isn't anyone who can win the
"which one is Hikaru- kun game."
どっちが光君でしょうかゲームを当てられる奴なんて
いやしないんだ
We've known that from the start!
そんなの最初から分かってるんだ
Then whenever anyone guesses wrong,
だったら外した時
why do you always look so sad?
なんでいつも寂しそうな顔をする
That's right. I remember.
そうだ　思い出した
You're Hikaru- kun.
こっちが光君
You guessed wrong.
外れだよ
After that, the girl said...
そのあと　あの女の子は言った
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい　泣かないでね
Don't cry, okay?
I remember how surprised
I was when I heard those words.
その言葉を聞いて
僕は驚いたのを覚えている
We probably looked like
we were about to cry at the time.
たぶん　僕らはその時
泣き出しそうな顔をしていたのだろう
Even if I'm not able to do it,
someday, somewhere,
たとえ俺には無理だとしても
いつかどこかで
somebody may show up who
is able to tell you apart.
お前たちを見分けてくれる人が現われるかもしれない
Still, this much is certain.
だがこれだけは確かだ
If you keep staying in your
own little world from now on,
ずっとこれからも　ふたりきりの世界にいたら
you will never run into the people
who are able to tell you apart.
永遠にお前たちを見分けられる人たちに出会えない
So instead, why don't we open
the doors of the Host Club together?
なら一緒に
ホスト部の扉を開こうじゃないか
Let's try to expand your world, together.
一緒に　世界を広げてみよう
Our first meeting will be after
the opening ceremony, after school.
第一回のミーティングは始業式の放課後
We're having it in the high
school's music room #3.
楽室でやるからな
That day, after his highness offered
an exceptionally correct answer,
その日　見事に大正解を言ってのけた殿に
unconsciously, we were a little bit
僕らは不覚にもちょっとだけ
ほんのちょっとだけ
- just a little bit -
impressed by him.
感動してしまったりした
わあ すごい学校
Wow, this school is incredible.
"Admissions Guide"
Even if I do get in here,
こんなとこ受かっても　うまくやっていけるかなあ
will I really be able to get by okay?
Is that right? Takashi, you were
invited by Suou- kun, too?
そうか　崇も須王君に誘われたんだ
Yeah.
You know what? He said it was
okay for me to like cute things.
あのね　僕ね　可愛い物好きでもいいんだって
He said it was okay for me to like cake.
ケーキ好きでもいいんだって
I'm not sure what to do.
僕　どうしようかなあ
Mitsukuni, you can do whatever you want.
光邦の思うとおりにすればいい
Mm-hmm, you're right.
うん　そうだね
Well, I guess something will work out.
ま　なんとかなるか
Now, to work towards
the entrance exams next year.
来年受験頑張ろうっと
"And so, one month later"
"after school, following
the opening ceremony"
Remember, Kaoru,
いいか　馨
it's not like we were impressed
by what that fool lord said.
あのお馬鹿な殿のいうことに感動したわけじゃないぞ
I know. We're simply here to kill time.
分かってるよ
単なる暇潰しだ
そう　そうとも　暇潰しさ
Yeah, exactly.
We're killing time.
It's just possible that no one will
ever turn up in your whole life
もしかしたら　あんたらを本当に見分ける奴なんて
that can really tell you two apart.
一生現われないかもね
You're right, lady.
そうだよ　お姉さん
There's nobody in the whole world
who is able to tell us apart.
僕らを見分けられる奴なんて
この世界にはいない
I'm sure there's nobody.
きっといないんだ
I understand that. And yet...
それは分かってる　けど…
Well, let's open them together.
じゃ一緒に開けるよ
Mm-hmm.
Ready, set...
セーノ
And so, we opened the door.
そして僕たちはその扉を開けた
我がホスト部は今日からスペシャルハロウィンウィークとなる
Starting today, the Host Club
is having a special Halloween week!
Oh, we're going to...
あっ　僕たち
... miss our club activities,
because of our class event.
クラスのイベントで部活休むから
待て待て　なんでハルヒまで連れて行く
Wait, wait, why are you
taking Haruhi with you!?
Next time, " Until the Day
When it Becomes a Pumpkin"
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ　来週も
お待ちしております